# **Dmitry Pershin**

#### visa sponsorship required

✓ dapper1291@gmail.com

+7 912 618 5850

Yekaterinburg, Russian Federation

Date of birth: December 20 1991

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/dapper91

https://github.com/dapper91

https://dapper91.github.io



Software engineer with more than five years of experience working on projects from different areas like cybersecurity, cloud computing, bank services; looking to become a part of an experienced developer team to work on innovative software and services.

## Education

> Ural State Technical University, M.S. in computer science, faculty of radio engineering, summa cum laude

#### Experience

#### Python software engineer at Tochka Bank / 05.2019 – present

Tochka Bank is the most successful russian digital (online) bank oriented on providing Internet services

- Designed, developed and launched a quick payments service from scratch. Quick payments service is financial infrastructure that provides an ability to make payments in near-real-time using a QR-code (merchant side) and a mobile phone app (customer side) connected to a customer bank account without using cash or plastic cards.
- > Took part in development of financial analysis web tools backend that helped entrepreneurs to possess comprehensive information about theirs financial statistics. The tools provided a lot of visual information like graphs and tables based on statistical analisys, classification and clusterization algorithms that helped out customers to reduce their expenses. As a result the service received positive user feedback and most of the customers extended theirs trial subscription.

#### Python Software Engineer at Yandex / 11.2018 – 05.2019

Yandex is a russian multinational corporation specializing in Internet-related products and services

- > Took part in development of a high-performance task scheduler SAAS that provided optimal company cluster resources utilization which reduced company expenses. The service was able to store several petabytes of user data using multiple data center replication and sharding mechanism.
- > Took part in development and improvement of service API and SDK providing an ability to describe complex execution pipelines on several thousand of servers in multiple data centers providing high availability 24/7.

#### Python / C++ Software Engineer at USSC Ltd. / 08.2016 – 11.2018

Ural Security Systems Center is one of the leading russian cybersecurity companies specialized in enterprise information security services.

- > Took part in development of software for industrial networks cybersecurity analysis, malware attacks prevention and network traffic inspection. The product was able to detect cyberattacks on enterprise networks and helped in incident investigation at critical facilities providing introspective analysis features like network traffic dump, security events and access log analysis.
- > Rewritten some security modules from multi-threaded to asynchronous execution model which greatly increased software performance and made it possible to monitor much more production facilities without hardware update.
- > Developed a module that used SCAP (security content automation protocol) standard to analyze OS integrity and protection using open world-wide vulnerability database which let to detect 0-day vulnerabilities as soon as possible.

### Skills

Languages	Databases	Frameworks	vcs	Other	
> Python	> PostgreSQL	> asyncio	> Git	> Linux	> SQL
> C/C++	> MongoDB	> aiohttp		> Docker	> BASH
> Rust	> Redis	> Flask		> Kubernetes	> Machine Learning
> Swift	> Elasticsearch	> scikit-learn		> RabbitMQ	> Distributed Systems
				> Kafka	